Lorenzo Girardi

SRE Team Manager



PERSONAL DETAILS

Lorenzo Girardi Via cacciatori delle alpi 19 Castronno (Varese) italy

M: 00393402892734

E: lorenzo.girardi@gmail.com PGP

E: lorenzo@ethzero.it

E: I@k8s.it

W: www.k8s.it
W: github
W: grafana

DOB: 16/02/1983 Driving license: YES Nationality: Italian

AREAS OF EXPERIENCE

Site reliability engineer

<u>Datacenter management</u>

People management

Business projects

Virtualization technology

Networking

Cloud

Operating systems

High Traffic infrastructures

Monitoring

<u>Observability</u>

Kubernetes

PCI DSS

Automation

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Highly competent and organized technology site reliability engineer manager with experience in high scalability/availability on-prem, hybrid and pure cloud.

Management of large projects and implementations with the latest smart tools coordinating multiple teams.

Extensive knowledge of monitoring/observability, applications behavior and data security within guidelines to ensure compliance and report on possible improvements .

Managing teams, in order to reach the business goal and grow the skills. Interested in a new challenges, opportunity and job reality in a large and complex company with high traffic.

Continuously improving my knowledge on new technologies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SRE Team Manager - BravoNEXT sa

jan 2019 - present

SRE Team Leader - BravoNEXT sa

mid 2016 - 2018

System administrator - BravoNEXT sa

jan 2012 - mid 2016

Acting as manager and technical lead to identify and implement new projects in a large heterogeneous environment.

Duties:

- Shape infrastructure environment
- Drive teams to strive for success
- Design new technology to improve the business
- Technology abstraction to make easy the usage
- Planning building with KPI and milestone roadmap
- Infrastructure as a code
- Sponsoring "keep it simple"
- "If it isn't there, it can't break"
- Sponsoring observability to create SLI SLO SLA
- Create awareness of the products
- Design for failure

Architecture

Infrastructure as a code

PERSONAL SKILLS

Technically minded

Pro-active

Analytical

My work is also my hobby

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

<u>java – tomcat – jboss –springboot – javamelody – jmx</u>

<u>.net - iis - sql server - cluster</u> <u>WSFC - alwaysON - iis ARR -</u> <u>cluster NLB</u>

<u>apache - mod balancer - mod</u> <u>proxy balancer - mod jk - mod</u> <u>cluster</u>

<u>nginx - vts module - ingress -</u> traefik - kong - haproxy

vmware esxi - veeam backup / replication

<u>rhev - ovirt</u>

AWS - s3 - vpc - peering loadbalancer - cloudformation opsworks - api gateway

<u>Azure – powershell cli – database</u> <u>as service</u>

<u>rundeck - spacewalk - ansible -</u> <u>terraform - packer - spinnaker</u>

Monitoring - nagios handlers cacti - grafana - collectd telegraf - statsd - influxdb carbon - graphite - prometheus cortex - loki

<u>Idap – active directory – bind –</u> domain trust – domain hierarchy -

- Roles mindset oriented based on MS Active directory, adfs, openIdap, oauth
- Linux machines orchestration
- Windows server orchestration
- Virtualization infrastructure based on rhev/ovirt and vmware
- Kubernetes infrastructure management on-prem / hybrid /cloud
- Network management ipsec open source strongswan , openswan and cisco and fortinet
- PCI DSS management and improvements
- Extensive knowledge of kubernetes and microservices
- Analysis and advantages of hybrid cloud
- Infrastructure as a code with the most useful tool based on company strategy / teams / engagements

System administrator - Luxury Goods International LGI sa

contractor Temera sa 2011-2012 contractor IT Time sa 2010-2011

managing and responsible of end users tools, vpn cisco, active directory structure, lotus domino server and a first levelcontact for as400

Duties:

- Managing Mail Server Domino
- Management of mobile service on Blackberry
- Configuration and management VPN Cisco
- Active Directory management GPO
- AS400 jda , jd Edwards

System administrator - Eprice srl

2008-2010

System administrator CED Gallarate and business farm Milano

Duties:

- Management remote data center on Colt (Milano) iNET (Settimo Milanese)
- Configuration windows and linux server based on vmware esx4 and esxi 4.1
- Deploy and configuration windows server 2000, 2003, 2008 standard enterprise for business solution
- Deploy and configuration linux server for advanced internal

adfs - oauth - saml

openvpn – strongswan –
openswan – site to site – road
warriors – traffic shaping – traffic
inspection

k8s - kubernetes - docker flanneld - etcd - service mash apigw - containerd - kubespray hpa - autoscaling

google cloud platform

solution (samba server, hw monitoring, performance monitoring, web employee portal, vpn server)

- Iscsi and fiber storage configuration and management
- Configuration and management of workstations working on Windows Xp e Windows 7.
- Server backup management tape DELL
- Network develop for company and other 30+ corner site

OTHER LANGUAGES

	Understanding		Speaking		Writing
	Listening	Reading	Interaction	Production	
English	B2	B2	B2	B2	B2
French	A2	A2	A2	A2	A2

EDUCATION

- 2003-2008
 Università degli studi dell'Insubria facoltà di informatica Information technology
- 1997- 2002 Pier Luigi Nervi I.T.Geometri